两分钟后会给您直播  殿下
You're live in two minutes. Your Royal Highness
谢谢
Thank you
您肯定会有出色的表现  您慢慢来
I am sure you will be splendid. Just take your time.
时间到了
Time to go.
下午好
Good afternoon.
殿下  3次灯闪之后  持续灯亮表示直播开始
Your Majesty, 3 flashes, and steady red means you're live.
打扰一下  医生  这样做的目的是什么？
Excuse me, Doctor. What is the purpose of this?
你好  有人在吗？
Hello. Is anyone there?
我正上厕所
I'm just in the loo.
约翰逊夫人你好  过来了啊
Hello Mrs Johnson, there you are.
不过您迟到了
But I'm afraid you're late.
公开讲话是我丈夫的职责之一
My husband is required to speak publicly.
约克公爵？
The Duke of York?
是的  约克公爵
Yes. the Duke of York.
殿下
Your Royal Highness.
当然
Of course.
我能治好您的丈夫
I can cure your husband.
你能什么时候开始？
When can you start?
是你让我开得太慢了，爸爸！
You make me drive too slowly, Dad!
下午我有稀客来访
I had a special visitor this afternoon.
我能离开座位了吗？
May I be please leave the table?
一个英俊的王子！
A handsome prince!
一个短尾巴的信天翁
A short-tailed Albatross.
晚安
Good night
他是认真的？
Is he serious?
谢谢
Thank you.
你可以在这儿等你妈妈
You can stay here and wait for your mum.
我听说不能坐的太近
I was told not not to sit too close.
你最早的回忆是什么？
What was your earliest memory?
什么时候开始结巴的？
When did the defect start?
我从小就这样！
I've always been this way!
我很怀疑
I doubt that.
什么时候开始的？
When did it start?
这很典型
That's typical.
别开玩笑了
Don't be ridiculous.
自言自语的时候呢？
How about when you talk to yourself?
当你自言自语的时候，结巴吗？
when you talk to yourself, do you stammer?
当然不会！
Of course not!
这说明你的缺陷不是不可改变的
That proves your impediment isn't a permanent part of you.
这我读不了
I can't read this.
我还没完呢
I haven't finished yet.
我要录下你的声音
I'm going to record your voice
我怎么听到我说什么？
How can I hear what I'm saying?
录音是免费的
The recording is free.
上帝保佑你们
God bless you.
你也试试
Have a go yourself.
恭喜您，陛下
Congratulations, Sir.
谢谢
Thank you.
坐正了，挺起腰
Sit up, straight back,
他说她让他由衷的开心
He said she made him sublimely happy.
那我怎么听到我说什么？
How can I hear what I'm saying?
我下周来找你？
Shall I see you next week?
我要每天都见你
I shall see you every day.
深呼吸，扩张胸部
Take a nice deep breath, expand the chest
把手放到肋骨上
Put your hands on your ribs
深吸气，好
Deeper, good
加油，再试一次，伯蒂
come on, one more time, Bertie
你能行的
you can do it
你去哪儿了？
Where've you been?
我来开车
I'll drive.
没有，乔治
No, George.
华莉丝非常想念我
Wallis misses me terribly.
妈妈说你吃晚饭迟到了
Mama says you're late for dinner.
谢谢
Thank you
这么想真可怜
It's such a sad thought.
我一直在练习，每天一小时
I've been practising. One hour a day.
这是怎么回事？
What's going on there?
我准备点热牛奶
I'll put on some hot milk.
我哥哥
My brother.
我和大卫很亲近
David and I were very close.
大卫取笑过你吗？
Did David ever tease you?
你是天生习惯右手吗？
Are you naturally right handed?
那肯定不好受
That must have been painful.
家里人谁和你最亲近？
Who were you closest to in your family?
这都怪你
This is your fault.
真高兴见到你们俩
How lovely to see you both.
欢迎来到我们的乡村小屋
Welcome to our little country shack.
我是应国王的邀请而来
I came at the invitation of the King.
陛下
Your Majesty
见到您很高兴，辛普森太太
Very nice to see you, Mrs Simpson
你好，大卫
Hello David.
是么
Really?
那谁来摆平希特勒？
Who'll sort out Herr Hitler?
这一点都不好笑
That's not funny.
我们想要结婚
We intend to marry
什么？
Excuse me?
我的天哪
Good God.
究竟大卫哪一点让你说不出话来？
What is it about David that stops you speaking?
滚开！
Bugger off!
因为我很生气！
Because I'm angry!
我们出去透透气吧
Let's get some air.
我知道我的位置！
I know my place!
这是谋反！
That is treason!
我只想让你明白，你没必要被恐惧束缚手脚
I'm trying to get you to realize you need not be governed by fear.
我受够了！
I've had enough of this!
你在怕什么？
What're you afraid of?
那你还来找我？
Why'd you come to me?
不单单因为她是美国人
It's not just because she's an American.
国王能否避免私生活影响自己的职责？
Can the King separate his personal life from his public duty?
很抱歉，罗格先生，公爵现在很忙
I'm very sorry, Mr Logue,the Duke is busy
我告诉过您，公爵非常忙
As I said, the Duke is terribly busy.
多谢
Thank you
我很抱歉，没有其他的方案了
I'm afraid there's no other way.
我一定要娶她
I must marry her.
你们肯定会喜欢的
I'm sure you'll love it.
陛下
Your Majesty.
别担心了
Don't worry about that
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
需要茶水吗，夫人？
Would you like some tea, Ma'am?
我自己来吧
I'll help myself.
我看了布告了
I've seen the placards
他们指的不是我
They don't mean me.
我的前任现在不仅活着，还活得好好的
My predecessor is not only alive, but very much so.
他已经不在了
He's not here anymore.
你现在已经完全自己做主了，伯蒂
You're very much your own man, Bertie.
伯蒂，你过来
Bertie, come here
见到您很高兴
It's very nice to meet you.
欢迎您，陛下
Welcome your Majesty.
罗格医生需要参加加冕礼
Dr. Logue will be attending the Coronation.
可您的家人将坐在那里，陛下
But members of your Family will be seated there, Sir.
这位先生，这里可是威斯敏斯特教堂！
My dear fellow, this is Westminster Abbey!
教会一定要为陛下做好准备
The Church must prepare his Majesty.
我的准备同样重要
My preparations are equally important.
这也是我的意思，大人
Those are my wishes, Your Grace.
陛下
Your Majesty.
准备好了？开始吧
Everything alright? Let's get cracking.
我尝试了肌肉治疗、练习、放松
I did muscle therapy, exercise, relaxation,
我的工作，是给他们说话的自信
My job was to give them faith in their voice
你这样太拔高自己了
You give a very noble account of yourself.
你让这国家的国王不能说话
you've saddle this nation with a voiceless King.
人们还往上刻名字呢！
People have carved their name into it!
因为我有发表意见的权利！
Because I have a right to be heard!
你是我认识的最勇敢的人
you're the bravest man I know.
你会成为一个相当好的国王
you'll make a bloody good king.
这究竟是怎么回事，陛下？
What on earth's going on, Sir?
大主教，没事的
It's quite all right, Archbishop.
谢谢，伯蒂
Thank you Bertie.
非常好，非常好，大主教
Very good, very good. Archbishop.
爸爸，他在说什么？
Papa, what's he saying?
稿子已经经过了审核
The wording is fully approved.
首相也会在广播节目中和您一起出席
The Prime Minister will be joining you for the broadcast
这是我儿子劳里
This is my son Laurie
非常感谢，谢谢
Thank you very much. Thank you
再来
Try again.
那我就是历史上最庄重的国王了
Then I'm the solemnest king who ever lived.
这我做不成
I can't do this.
很高兴能这么快再次见面
Nice to see you again, so soon.
亲爱的
Darling
伍德先生
Mr Wood.
祝您好运，陛下
Good luck, Your Majesty.
伍德先生
Mr Wood.
来点新鲜空气
Some fresh air.
好了，亲爱的
There you are, darling.
说给我这个朋友听
Say it to me, as a friend.
祝贺您，陛下，专业的播音员水准
Congratulations, your Majesty. A true broadcaster.
谢谢，伍德先生
Thank you, Mr Wood.
恭喜陛下
Congratulations, your Majesty.
谢谢
Thank you.
非常好
Perfect
你的第一次战时演讲，祝贺你
Your first war time speech. Congratulation.
谢谢，罗格
Thank you, Logue.
陛下，您让我哑口无言
Your Majesty, I'm speechless.
祝贺您，陛下
Congratulations, Sir
先生们
Gentlemen.
爸爸表现如何，伊丽莎白？
So how was Papa, Elizabeth?
开头停了会，不过后面好的多
Halting at first, but you got much better.
上帝保佑你
Bless you.
你很了不起，爸爸
You were just splendid, Papa.
你们都准备好了？
You're all ready?
国王在战争中的每次演讲，都有莱诺陪在身边
Lionel was with the King for every wartime speech.
这些广播，使乔治六世成为了英国抵抗精神的代言人
Through his broadcasts, George VI became a symbol of national resistance.
莱诺和伯蒂在余生中一直维持着亲密的友谊
Lionel and Bertie remained friends for the rest of their lives.